Give it a shot!
about one of the most probably famous and popular sagas
or franchises, up to date, Harry Potter.
Doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
All right, so Harry Potter.
It started with like what, six, seven years ago?
Oh, more than that I think.
Like 10 years ago?
It started maybe 10.
No, probably eight years ago.
Eight years ago with the books, right?
All these, the series of children's books
that was just so popular.
And so they started with the books
and this girl, the author is from England
and it became really popular.
I've never seen people so, especially children,
so anxious to read.
I mean, they were waiting outside the bookstores
for the sequels and it was an amazing phenomenon.
So now we're gonna be looking at Harry Potter
and the Half-Blood Prince.
This is the sixth movie.
All right, so not only are there like seven books
but there's gonna, there are going to be in total
seven movies and they've already done six of them.
And so the first one, they're all kind of pre-teen,
kind of awkward, they're at the school for the first time
and then you kind of follow them along.
And this last one is, well, we all have
different opinions on it, but let's hear it.
Who liked the movie?
All right, who liked it?
Did you like it?
I thought the first two were well-made
and well-presented because the whole idea seemed new.
So everyone liked it, everyone wanted to see it.
It was one of the most-
Magic was in.
This is one of the most anticipated movies
but I think now it's getting a bit tiring.
Yeah, I think after six-
I didn't like the new one, just in case anyone wants to.
Okay, you didn't like it, what about you?
I liked certain elements about the new one
and mostly the last ones, I've always liked
more than the whole movie, just certain elements
and certain things that are happening.
Catherine?
I didn't like it, I thought it was filler.
Filler is like something that you make
to make a place between the last one
and the next one, so this is kind of like,
oh, we have to make a movie
but the really exciting movie is gonna be number seven.
So I just thought it was so boring.
So you can kind of skip it and just read the summary.
Well, you can't skip it,
there's a very important thing that happens
but that's the only important thing
and there's no real climax,
there's no real event at the end of the movie.
It's just like, oh, and then we're back, it's cool.
All right, so just to give you the synopsis of the movie,
Voldemort is tightening his grip
on both the muggle world and the wizards at Hogwarts.
Hogwarts is the school, right?
Hogwarts is the school, muggles are the human beings,
they're not magical and wizards are everywhere else.
So Harry Potter is kind of reluctant
to go back to Hogwarts because of what happened
in the previous movie, right?
Yeah.
So he's kind of afraid, he doesn't really know
who to trust but he discovers a book, right?
This book of the Half-Blood Prince.
That's when he gets back to school.
Diary, is it not?
No, it's a chemistry book but it has corrections
that somebody made because there are certain potions
that give certain directions but they are not so accurate
so they have corrections and certain new spells as well.
And all the answers to the questions in class
so he becomes the star of this new class.
So he just improvises on the older spells.
So he's just stealing spells.
Everybody doesn't know who the Half-Blood Prince is
because there's no other name.
This is the mystery in the movie, right?
We want to discover who this is.
But in the end, evil, very evil.
All right, and another new element to the movie is that,
well, there's love in the air.
Well, not only are people getting more,
well, things are getting more dangerous
but people are also getting more mature
and they're starting to have relationships.
So they're not these little 12-year-olds
like they were eight years ago.
Now they're almost adults.
They're pimply teens.
And actually, this is one of the biggest controversies
in the movie is that people complained
in the scene where they're drinking beer.
Really?
Yeah, because it's a kid's movie
and children are watching it
and they're saying how can,
it's like having a Disney movie
where people drink beer.
Yeah, obviously it's not a good message to send across.
You could just say it's ginger beer
which is non-alcoholic.
It's non-alcoholic beer.
Or magic beer.
Magic beer.
They magically take out the alcohol.
All right, so.
One of the things is that they are supposed to be younger.
In the movies, each time,
they're only supposed to age one year.
Right now they're supposed to be 16
but they're actually all 20.
They look like they're 20 as well.
They do.
Well, that's part of the problem.
No, they are.
Because it takes two, three years to make a movie.
They actually are 20 because one of the things
is that I read about the main actor of Harry Potter
and he was born the exact same day as I was.
Really?
The same year.
The same year, exact same day.
So you're the same age and every time a movie comes out
he's another two years older
but in the book he's only supposed to be a year older.
In the book he's supposed to be right now 16 or 17.
Well, do you think when the next movie comes out,
part seven, will it be the end of Harry Potter?
Will we not see him again?
Or do you think they're gonna come out with like...
They're supposed to have two movies
to divide the last book.
So we're gonna have, out of six books,
we're gonna have nine movies.
Out of seven books.
Seven books.
Eight movies.
Well, and the thing is JK Rowling, the author,
made so much money.
How could someone not want to make more money?
You know, obviously it makes sense to make more movies.
But it's like, for example, Lord of the Rings.
They did the three books they did in three movies.
But Tolkien's dead.
You know, like it makes me think of Sherlock Holmes,
the author of Sherlock Holmes.
He, in one story, killed Sherlock Holmes.
He said, that's it.
I don't wanna write Sherlock Holmes stories anymore.
People were so upset that they made him bring
new Sherlock Holmes back to life.
And he had to write a number of new stories.
And so, I think something similar might happen
with Harry Potter where you have a revival.
So that people didn't know,
they're also working on a Sherlock Holmes movie.
Yeah, yeah, they are.
Yeah, I heard about that.
That's gonna be interesting.
I'm kind of excited.
I like Guy Ritchie, who is directing it.
All right, so, well, now,
so what do you think will happen in parts of...
Well, we obviously know, right?
The book has been released.
We know how it ends, right?
Yeah, are we allowed to talk about that on the show?
Well, let's not spoil it, but if you hadn't,
or if you don't know how the saga ends,
what do you think would happen after this?
I don't know.
There's gonna be a showdown with the one
who must not be named...
Do you think Harry Potter can get killed?
I think so.
I think if he does, it's gonna have something
to do with the whole Phoenix rising from the ashes.
All of this death is not gonna be permanent.
He's gonna live on...
He's also kind of a Jesus figure,
if you wanna go there.
I don't know if you wanna go there.
Yeah, it could be.
He's got this scar, he's the chosen one,
he's recognized as being special,
so if you're thinking about this as being
kind of a Jesus story, then yes,
he's probably gonna die and come back to life.
And yeah.
Yeah, he's gonna come back.
It's kind of like all of these franchise movies.
Have you read the books?
No, no.
Okay.
But we're talking about, like, out of the book,
just what we think of right now.
I don't think the studio will allow
them to kill Harry Potter.
I think it would be too upsetting for children.
But I haven't read the books, to be honest,
but I don't think that the studios would accept
a completely different story from the books
because people go crazy.
You know, people love the books,
and so if you change the books too much,
they get really angry.
That's true.
And I once read that, I think it was Stephen King
that sent a letter to the author, like,
saying, don't kill Harry Potter.
Really?
Yeah.
It was before they released the last one.
Really?
See, I'm not very, I'm not much of a Harry Potter fan.
I've actually haven't watched all of the movies.
I think I watched something about the Cup of Fire.
Goblet of Fire.
The Goblet of Fire, yeah.
That was pretty cool.
It was interesting.
I like the scene where they're flying in their brooms
and having, like, battles and then in the stadium.
That was kind of cool.
They're, like, finding a dragon or whatever.
Quidditch, yeah.
The game of Quidditch.
Yeah, see, you guys are nerds about this stuff.
No, it does happen.
No, I'm actually not a huge fan either,
but, you know, you watch six movies,
they're all the same, so you learn the words.
Every movie, they play Quidditch, and every movie,
always every movie.
Okay, tell me a spell.
And there's something you wish to hear me say.
Expecto Pectronas.
I don't know, maybe I didn't say that.
Wingardium La Viosa.
Yeah.
La Viosa, yeah.
Bombarda.
It was in the first movie.
Yeah, Bombarda.
Wingardium La Viosa.
Bombarda.
What is the one that you can kill a person by?
Abracadabra.
Now it's not.
Yeah, it is.
It's Abracadabra or something like that.
Is it that lame?
Yeah, because there's a spell that I read.
Abracadabra.
That's it.
It's a spell that you just wave the wand, the person dies.
And there's another one where you can torture someone.
It's called cruxio.
Cruxio.
Oh, like cruxio.
Wow, I wonder where she gets these words from.
They kind of sound Latin.
I think she's kind of, ooh, stunning.
I guess one of the writers is Spanish.
She's fiddling with Latin.
Yeah.
So she's taking Latin words
and she's kind of like, more than that.
Mixing them around.
If one of the writers might be of Spanish origin.
Maybe.
All right, so Gulam, in three adjectives,
how would you describe the movie?
Dark.
Intriguing.
Okay.
Quite fast, I would say.
Fast.
Yeah, fast pace, okay.
Fast pace, yeah.
What about you, Bryant?
Twisted.
Twisted, wow.
Well, yeah, in the sense that it's like,
in the first movie and all of them,
you don't really know what to expect of this teacher.
Professor Snake?
Snake.
Yeah, Snake.
Professor Snake.
You don't know what to expect of Professor Snake.
Like, in the first one, you think maybe he's evil
and then so on.
You don't really know.
You think he's good again, but then he's bad.
And then in the end, he looks like he's gonna be good again.
So it's like all the time turning around.
Twisted and confusing.
Yes, confusing.
What else?
One more.
And I would say it was a little bit monotonous.
Yes, monotonous.
It was monotonous?
Yes.
So that's like, how would you explain monotonous?
It's all the same.
Mono, mono means the same.
So it's pretty much saying that it's the same thing
over and over again.
Yeah, exactly.
At the same time, you don't get anything
that really thrills you in the whole movie.
It's like, it doesn't really get to any high point
where you're like, whoa.
That was amazing.
We must have seen most of it in the earlier movies,
so there's not one new to offer.
And what about you, Catherine?
I'm gonna be mean here.
All right.
Boring, boring, boring.
Wow.
All right, so what grade would you give this movie?
Okay, it's pretty.
I like the snow scene when they're outside in the snow.
And I like the Ron's parents' house,
that scene with the big circle, the magic circle.
So it's pretty.
So for that reason, I'd give it a C.
Okay, a C.
Wow, that's still pretty bad.
What about you guys?
It's average.
Yeah, it's like almost below average.
What do you give it?
I would give it an average, I don't know,
like a B, B-minus or something.
B-minus, all right.
That's generous.
What about you, Gulen?
I would go with the B-minus.
It's not something you might wanna miss,
or you'd rather watch it.
It's worth the money, I would say.
It's worth paying for the ticket.
You have to see what happens
if you wanna see the next one.
And I wanna see the next one,
so I don't regret seeing it.
I agree with Gulen on that point.
I guess maybe because I paid, I think it's worth watching.
Use that in the movie theater.
Yeah, I decide.
All right, so it's worth the seven bucks or 10 bucks
or whatever that it costs to go to the movie theater.
I would say it's not a waste of money, though.
All right.
It's money while it's spent.
Well, and if you haven't watched it,
maybe you can wait until the DVD comes out.
Maybe it's like five bucks or something like that.
All right, guys, so that's all for today.
If you have any suggestions, any comments,
or any observations about this show,
or if you have any movies you would like to analyze,
please send us an email at englishpod
at praxislanguage.com,
or visit our website at englishpod.com.
Thank you, guys.
Yeah, we look forward to hearing from you on the site
and definitely post your opinions.
Yeah.
Because ours are not the correct opinions.
That's the nice thing about opinions.
Everyone has their own.
Exactly, yeah.
We'll see you guys there.
And one thing, if by any chance Emma Watson,
or somebody that knows her is listening,
then she should know that I really have a crush on her.
You're a big fan, all right.
Aww.
Just a huge crush.
Papila.
Maybe she is listening if you can come to the website.
Well, I think she's English.
She is an English speaker.
I think she's okay.
I'm not encouraging spammers
to create fake profiles and stuff.
All right, guys, we'll see you there.
All right, bye, everyone.
Bye, everyone.